now let's say if we're given an equation
in point slope
form how can we graph this equation on a
coordinate
plane what would you do in order to
graph
it now the first thing you should do is
identify the
slope and the point
the XY ordered pair so here's the
original
equation so we can see that the slope is
equal to
two so m is
two and then we can see that
X1 is positive 1 not negative 1 but
positive 1 and y1 is posi 3 so we have
the
point 1 comma 3 X is 1 and Y is 3 so
what you want to do is plot the point
first 1 comma 3 is over here and the
slope is equal to
two that means as you travel one unit to
the right you need to go up two
units so the next point is going to be
at 2 comma 5 so if you go one to the
left you need to go down to
units now granted this Line's not going
to be perfectly straight but you get the
picture and then just connect them with
a straight
line let's try another
example so let's say if we have this
equation y + 3 is equal to 32 * x +
4 so identify the slope and the point we
can see that the slope is equal to 3
over2 now what's X1 and what's
y1 X1 is -4 y1 is3 basically you just
got to change the sign of these numbers
if you see a plus4 make it a Nega four
if you see a positive three make it a
negative3 if you see a negative3 make it
a positive three so just reverse the
signs and you're going to get the point
which is4 comm3
so now we can go ahead and plot
it the first point is at
-43 and the slope is 3 over
two three is the rise two is the
run so we're going to travel two units
to the right and we're going to go up
three units
so the next point that we're going to
get is -2 Comm 0 x is -2 Y is
z so now let's use the slope again let's
travel two units to the right and let's
go up three units so this will take us
to the
point0 comma
3 which is a y intercept of
three and now let's connect these points
so now you know how to graph a linear
equation in point slope form so all you
need to do is find the X and Y values of
the point the first point that you need
to plot and then use the slope to get
the next
Point all you need is two points if you
have two points you can draw a straight
line if you want at the third Point
that's fine too but you just need two
points at minimum to graph a straight
line